Congcong Wang

linkedin.com/in/congcong-wang-68a565172 https://github.com/wangcongcong123 wangcongco@gmail.com (+353) 83412-8928

ABSTRACT

I am a PhD candidate in the School of Computer Science, UCD, under the supervision of Dr. David Lillis. My PhD research focuses on exploring computational techniques to process big crisis data on social media, which can help humanitarian advocates gain situational awareness and actionable information to improve their decision-making processes better.

EDUCATION

University College Dublin, Ireland Sept. 2018 – Expected, 2022 Ph.D. School of Computer Science and Informatics(CSI)

- **Project Topic:** Filtering for information types and priority on social media during crisis.
- Scholarship: School of Computer Science PG Grant.

University College Dublin, Ireland

Sept. 2017 - Jul. 2018

B.Sc. (Hons.) Software Engineering, First Class Honors, CSI (4th Year)

- Relevant Coursework: Data Analytics, Machine Learning, Computing Performance Evaluation, Contemporary Software Development, Cloud Storage, Operating Systems, Computer Network, Computer Security.
- Thesis: Evaluating Recommender Systems (A Grade).

Beijing University of Technology, China Sept. 2017 – Jul. 2018 Beijing-Dublin International College (1st – 3rd Years)

• Relevant Coursework: Programming, Probability Theory, Linear Algebra, Advanced Mathematics, Data Structures and Algorithms, Information Retrieval, Software Engineering, Information Systems, Information Theory.

PROFESSIONAI SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL Research: NLP, Social Media Analytics, Machine Learning

General: Python, Java, MySQL, Web Building

Languages: Mandarin (First), English (Fluent), Spanish (Novice)

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2015 - Jun. 2017

Beijing-Dublin International College, China

• I was the seminar leader on the Information Retrieval course, responsible for support and assessment of 80 students.

Programming Instructor (Python) Sept. 2015 – Jun. 2016 YiXinXian Technology Education Company, China

 I was a Python instructor for one year, my duties included writing tutorials and assessing students. I adopted the use of funny storytelling to explain concepts to students.

PROJECTS

TREC Incident Streams 2019-A Participant Jan. 2019 – Jun. 2019 National Institute of Standards and Technology, U.S.

• I submitted four runs of classifying actionable categories of crisis-related tweets and estimating their criticality using ensemble learning techniques.

Research Assistant

Dec. 2016 - Jun. 2017

China Center for Information Industry Development, China

- I developed a library indexing and borrowing system. This was used for book indexing construction and research on Chinese-based book items retrieval techniques.
- This project won 2nd place prize for the China Software Cup.

PUBLICATIONS